Navi Sohi

Navi.K.Sohi@gmail.com • San Jose, CA https://plainjane20.github.io/ https://pithub.com/in/navisohi https://github.com/PlainJane20

Effective **Data Analyst** with hands-on experience evaluating decision support systems and determining best processes to make effective business decisions, standardize decision support functions, and translate requirements into applications that employ appropriate decision support and reporting tools. Talented technical expert specialized in proposing solutions to complex business problems and leading the implementation of recommended solutions. Demonstrated experience in strategic financial analyses to improve visibility, simplify reporting, improve data accuracy and integrity, establish core metrics, and inform strategic planning with continuous forecasting and modeling.

Education & Certifications

Bootcamp Certificate in Data Analytics & Visualization

University of California, Berkeley, Oct.2020 – Mar.2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, Machine Learning and more.

3.98 GPA | A+ letter grade

Certificate in Data Science

Data Camp | https://www.datacamp.com/ Certificate # 17,186,979

Certificate in Data Engineering

Data Camp | https://www.datacamp.com/ Certificate # 17,850,346

Certificate in Database Design

Data Camp | https://www.datacamp.com/ Certificate # 17,861,273

Bachelor of Science in Industrial and Organizational Psychology, Business Concentration

California State University, East Bay

Technical Proficiencies

Microsoft Office Suite, MS Visio, MS Excel, MS Access, MS Teams, MS SharePoint, G-Suite,

Software & Applications
PostgreSQL, PyCHarm, Git, Jupyter, Anaconda, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, SPSS,
Drupal, Crystal Reporting, Worldapp, Pattsy, Salesforce CRM, OLAP cubes, CPT Codes

Programming & Languages

Python, APIs, SQL, noSQL, MySQL, MongoDG, ETL, JSON, NumPy, SAS, MATLAB, C++, R,

Stata

Data Manipulation & Visualization

Pandas, Matplotlib, Tableau, Hadoop, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, D3, Leaflef, Plotly,

BeautifulSoup

Areas of Expertise

Data Collection & Analysis
 Continuous Process Improvement
 Automated Reporting & Tools
 KPIs & Benchmarking

System Administration
 Research Data Management
 Regression Analysis
 Statistical Analysis

Projects

Airline Delays and Cancellations Covid-19 | https://github.com/PlainJane20/ETL-Project-Flights-COVID-19.git Jan. 2021

Analysis of reported causes of flight delays and cancellations given the unprecedented impact of the COVID-19.

• Tools used: Jupyter Notebook, Python, Pandas, Seaborn, NumPy, SQAlchemy, SQLite, PostgreSQL

Mission to Mars | https://github.com/PlainJane20/Mission-To-Mars

Jan. 2021

Scrapped various NASA Mars related websites and displayed the data a website

• Tools used: Jupyter Notebook, Python, Pandas, Seaborn, NumPy, SQAlchemy, SQL, Flask and various APIs, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, D3, Plotly, Leaflet

Weather Visualization Dashboard | https://plainjane20.github.io/Web-Visualization-Dashboard-Latitude/ Jan. 2021 Web Visualization Dashboard of weather for over 540 cities at different latitudes relative to the equator line. The visualizations show temperature, humidity, cloudiness, and wind speed.

Tools used: Jupyter Notebook, Python, Pandas, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Matplotlib

Impact of Homelessness on Housing Prices | https://github.com/PlainJane20/Project-One.git

Nov. 2020

Homelessness is an continued issue which burden's our community across the globe, specially elevated with COVID. Goal of the project is to dive into factors that are related to homeleness and housing prices using various data available to us nationwide.

- Led a team of three in exploring multiple datasets: data cleaning, validation, and visualization.
- Analysis: relationship between real estate prices and homeless population; correlations, most feasible location
- Tools used: Jupyter Notebook, Python, Pandas, SciPy, Seaborn, Matlab, NumPy

Career Experience

Senior Decision Support Analyst

Sep. 2018 - Oct. 2020

Palo Alto Medical Foundation (PAMF), Mt. View, CA

Assessed the impact of strategic and financial decision points through complex modeling, data analytics, and reporting of large data sets. Led database administration, data interpretation, reporting and dashboards, analyzing data to assist in delivering optimal financial information, and communicating findings to key internal and external stakeholders. Developed and implemented optimized workflow processes to evaluate and calculate monthly and quarterly compensation and reconciliation with payroll. Engaged in strategic data analyses of compensation schemes and financial operations, including budgeting, planning, forecasting, and cost analyses to identify cost variances and improvements to billing processes. Reviewed and ensured the accuracy of analysis, compensation reports, earning statements, and other efforts aimed at measuring the organization's financial and operational performance.

Key Accomplishments & Responsibilities

- Engaged in interdepartmental collaboration to yield a 12% increase in efficiency of internal processes and workflows by applying continuous process improvement methodology and establishing automated reporting and tools.
- Successfully pinpointed \$4M in annual savings as the frontrunner for an analyst team tasked with developing customized reports to monitor performance for a network of 58 private practices across 15 specialties.
- Conducted Market Factor Analyses to collectively analyze productivity and compensation averages for over 1,200 physicians and benchmark against three years of national data.
- Delivered concise overviews of month-to-month financial status, up-to-date reporting of cash management, and profit and loss statements through accurate monthly financial reporting for a company with \$145M in annual revenue, allowing the company to leverage this information to make data-driven decisions.

HRIS Manager Mar. 2016 – Sep. 2018

Palo Alto Medical Foundation (PAMF), Mt. View, CA

Administrated and maintained optimal function of the organization's internal HR information services systems, including database management, network support, installation, customization, development, maintenance, and upgrades to applications,

systems, and modules. Served as the subject matter expert for all HR modules, including HCM, advanced compensation, benefits, time tracking, absence management, reporting, and onboarding. Advised executive leadership and HR staff on necessary improvements and enhancements to existing information services and databases, as well as recommendations and implementation of solutions. Managed all account services, including permissions, access, personalization, and system operations and settings for HRIS users. Programmed custom functions and documentation for specific tasks, including automated queries, filters, macros, and reporting.

Key Accomplishments & Responsibilities

- Project manager for internal tool P360 which includes all the data for new hire physicians, including but not limited to epic Ids, demographic info, tier leadership, credential info etc.
- Project manager for migrating Sutter APC's to PAMF; included building HRIS platform, payroll, benefits etc.
- Provided hands-on training, troubleshooting, and support for HR and business users, including creating and delivering comprehensive training materials, standard operating procedures (SOPs), and guidelines, ensuring compliance with all establishing processes and procedures.
- Prioritized data integrity, maintaining internal database files, tables, codes, backup files, and security through testing of system modifications, documenting processes, reporting, and promoting continuous process improvement.
- Applied industry leading project and change management methodologies and techniques to define project goals and scope, establish and execute a detailed project plan, identify, and mitigate risks, monitor, and control performance, and bring projects to successful closure in accordance with set resources, budget, and timeline.
- Facilitated efforts to prepare data for 401(k) discrimination testing and compliance with EEOC reporting, affirmative action, and required government reporting, including VETS 100 and Bureau of Labor and Statistics reporting.

Senior HR Benefits & Retirement Administrator

Jul. 2013 - Mar. 2016

Palo Alto Medical Foundation (PAMF), Mt. View, CA

Designed, implemented new benefits and retirement programs, such as group health, dental, vision, short-term and long-term disability, worker's compensation, life insurance, travel and accident plan, flexible spending plan, and various retirement plans.

Key Accomplishments & Responsibilities

- Project manager for Affordable Care Act (ACA) reporting tasks, including filing required information to the IRS, preparing monthly reports, and providing copies to recipients and employees.
- Advised over 1,300 physicians on benefits and retirement plans, such as cost analyses, cost variances, and auditing.
- Acted as the primary plan administrator for the physician 401(k), non-elective contributions, and cash balance plans, involving annual audits, 5500 filing, non-discrimination testing, and serving on the Retirement Plan Committee.
- Partnered with payroll team to accurately audit and reconcile employee contributions and data and complete any retroactive adjustments for each payroll to maintain compliance with internal controls.
- Supported the exit interview process, including documentation and final review of term checklists prior to final payroll.
- Documented, standardized, evaluated, and refined internal processes, policies, and operating procedures to reduce costs and increase efficiency.

Additional Experience

HRBP, Global Imagination, Campbell, CA

Trademark Administrator, Yahoo! Inc., Sunnyvale, CA

Patent Administrator, Hitachi GST, San Jose, CA